Ksenia Bataeva

Amsterdam, North Holland, Netherlands

kclosu@gmail.com

+31629465525

linkedin.com/in/ksenia-bataeva

Summary

Highly experienced software engineer turned into data scientist. Motivated to learn and grow continuously.

Skills & Tools: Python, Spark, SQL, GreenPlum, Kafka, Airflow, Docker, APIs, Data Warehousing, ETL, DataScience, Mathematical modelling, time series methods analysis, multivariate modelling

Technical Expertise:

- Background in full stack web application development (interfaces, backend, APIs and data modelling) and familiar with many modern development stacks as NodeJS, Python, PHP and frameworks (Django, Drupal, Laravel, Vue.js, React).
- Data Warehousing and Databases (PostgreSQL, GreenPlum, MongoDB, Redis, ElasticSearch).
- Measuring and analyzing marketing campaign performance.
- Proficient in predictive modelling, data processing and data mining algorithms.
- Capable of creating, developing, testing and deploying ML-models.
- Enjoy doing Data visualization and storytelling.

Experience



Senior Data Analyst

MY.GAMES

May 2021 - Present (1 year 2 months +)

- Analyze marketing campaign performance, track key metrics on a regular basis.
- Make cohort analysis.
- Built a user-level LTV model based on the first 7 days of user life, to understand which campaign drive the most value as soon as possible, which more accurate than previous cohort-based model.
- Help to define and build ETL processes in Hive, Spark, Python and Airflow for getting data into a form useful for analysis, dashboarding, and machine learning.
- Implemented MLOps tools.
- Have a working-level experience in Google Ads, automation fetching data from the API.

Senior Software Engineer

Information Analysis Center of EMERCOM of Russia

Feb 2019 - May 2021 (2 years 4 months)

- * Implemented a set of decoders for weather data and data pipelines for machine learning services (Python, Kafka, GreenPlum, Docker)
- * Build data-centric microservices to transform and join data from multiple sources and to integrate with other internal services.
- * Developed models to predict the river's water level (Prophet, LSTM, GradientBoosting)
- * Developed wildfire risk probability models
- * Doing a comparative analysis of the satellite-based indices like NDVI, NDWI, FWI, etc.

* Organized successful hackathons: track NoFloodWithAl on AlJ 2020 https://ai-journey.ru/2020/en/ contest/task02.html, https://emergencydatahack.ru, NoFireWithAl at Al Journey Contest 2021

Frontend Architect | Technical Lead

General research center of the Administrative Directorate of the President of the Russian Federation

Oct 2009 - Feb 2019 (9 years 5 months)

Education



Russian State Technological University named after K.E. Tsiolkovsky (MATI)

Master's degree, Applied mathematics and information technologies Sep 2006 - Jun 2012

Licenses & Certifications



Introduction to Statistics - Stepik

977930





Professional Data Analyst - DataCamp

Skills

Extract, Transform, Load (ETL) • Apache Spark • Machine Learning • Statistics • Airflow • Data Science • Python (Programming Language) • SQL • JavaScript • MLOps